PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

An accomplished marketing leader and a innovative sales with 15 years of experience in business-to-business sales, marketing, design and production. Proven results in effective communication with a determined focus on building relationships that increase sales and profit.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Sales: Business to Business sales. Enthusiastic and energetic team player with a proven track record. Personable and Professional. Able to attract key accounts and manage complex range of clients.
- Marketing: Increase market awareness through developing and designing creative programs to meet the changing needs of the customer.
- **Design:** Implement and design print material, signs, posters, banners and various marketing materials with the use of Photoshop, Illustrator, and Indesign software programs.
- **Production:** Results oriented, creative planning produced quality product with minimal waste of material through proof and knowledge of software.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Applied Proactive Technologies, Inc. \$\displaystyle \text{Springfield, MA}\$ (Dec 2009 to Present)

*Marketing**

Excelled in designing and communicating ideas and concepts to our utility customers to inspire and motivating their customers to buy energy efficient lighting and appliances.

- Work with the program managers on designing marketing programs for their utility clients.
- Responsible for the development of a brand identity for APT.
- Provide expert advise on the right printers for the right product and price for our utility customers.
- Train new program managers and program assistant on the policy and procedure for moving forward with new designs, orders and reorders of POP for the retails stores.
- Reduce errors on artwork, and pricing by streamlining a work flow of signatures and check points.
- Provide proper management for making schedules as well as production of marketing materials.
- Supply marketing information at many vital meetings and clients meetings.
- Implemented a Purchase Order system for our vendors.

Curtis1000 ♦ Newington, CT

Direct Marketing Consultant

(June 2007 - Sept 2009)

Proven track record of providing unique and highly effective communications that appealed to the emotional drivers of my customers with a clear call to action.

- Executed brand awareness through eye-catching personalized integrated communication channels.
- Delivered results through data, generational, and targeted audiences based on customer's criteria and needs.
- Provided a sales strategy that included targeting specific key accounts in retail, non-profits, education, financial and insurance markets.
- Acquired new customers and engaged existing accounts through customer service, emailing, cold calling, networking and webinars.
- Obtained and maintained existing clients through the education of alternative marketing methods that would obtain a higher ROI in their revenues.

XL Color Inc. \(\rightarrow \) Bloomfield, CT

(April 2005-June 2007)

Executive Sales Representative

Excelled in increased customer relations though achieving new accounts and maximized existing accounts with a full process management, including sales initiation, creativity in reviewing pre-production and advice through production to delivery.

- Implemented a strong post sale by a communication strategy that built strong customer relations which encouraged sales growth
- Achieved sales increase by expanding market opportunities beyond the company's sole key strength in large format digital banners. Implemented this goal by using my analytical ability to match the customer needs with new digital technologies provided by XL. This new expansion drove new volume and profit in the areas of vehicles wraps, store signs, and collateral pieces.
- Targeted potential high volume key accounts and continuously searched for avenues to penetrate their business with creative strategies that met and exceeded customer requirements. In January 2007, launched a new key account whose initial sale was \$750,000.00 and first year estimate \$1,000,000 plus.

Rich Signs and Designs \(\phi \) Wethersfield, CT

(Jan 1998 -April 2005)

- Partner
 - Played a major pivotal role in the start up, marketing, sales, design, and production for large format digital graphics company.
 - Generated new customer accounts through direct marketing strategies, networking, and cold calling.
 - Communicated design solutions for our customers in need of visual graphics for trade shows and promotional pieces.
 - Responsible for maintenance and service of 2 large format printers for our production department.
 - Implemented and produced final products based on specifications of our clients.
 - Formulated cost savings on materials, production and design through strategic planning.
 - Expedited all projects completed, for customer approval of final product.

Education & Training

Central Connecticut State University *BA in Marketing* Curtis Direct Mail Training Curtis Multi Channel Marketing

Computer Skills (Mac/PC)

Illustrator CS4 Indesign

PhotoshopCS4 All Microsoft office Products

Fleixsign 6.0

AFFILIATIONS

Glastonbury Rotary Club

Position Pubic Relations for all the events